JAVIER ALBERT

Data Science & Machine Learning

\$\bullet\$ +972 54 945 3540 @ jav.albert@gmail.com

\$\bullet\$ Tel Aviv, Israel

SUMMARY

I am a research engineer with strong programming skills and a solid background in statistics, physics and engineering. I am a multi-disciplinary professional who is passionate about using data, amazing visualizations, predictive models and creativity to approach complex real-life business problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Algorithms/Software Engineer

Applied Materials

10/2015 - 11/2017

Engineer at "Algorithmic Apps & Prototypes" group at the Algorithms Department. Responsible for the design, development, deployment and maintenance (full cycle) of scientific software solutions in the fields of:

- Signal processing, data exploration, pattern recognition and classification.
- Software Infrastructure (Matlab): Packages, code optimization, UI/UX.

Researcher

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology

1 07/2014 - 09/2015

Developed an optical system for solar panel characterization. Hardware assembling and software development in Matlab for data analysis.

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

Cointegration in cryptocurrency price series

Developed and tested an automated trading system based on statistical cointegration between cryptocurrencies price series. Part of the research is available at: https://goo.gl/xQBav1

Visualization: Making sense of 55 million taxi rides

Applied several visualization techniques to make sense of a Kaggle data set that contains 55 million taxi rides in NYC. The findings are currently being used to develop predictive models.

HANDS-ON CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning with TensorFlow

Google

• 5 courses. Certificate: https://goo.gl/ZATVjk

Data Science Professional Certificate

IBM

• 9 courses. Certificate: https://goo.gl/R8uXFv

TECHNOLOGIES



EDUCATION

MSc. in Electrical Engineering

Tel Aviv University

1 02/2016 - 02/2019

- Deep Learning (0510-7255)
- Machine Learning (0510-6205)
- Computer Vision (0510-6251)
- Estimation Theory (0510-6202)
- Random Processes (0510-5005)
- Multi-Dimensional Signal Processing (0510-6201)

BSc. in Physics

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology

10/2010 - 10/2015

BSc. in Materials Engineering

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology

2010 - 10/2015

OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS



Languages

Hebrew, English, Spanish, Italian and Portuguese



Psychometric Exam

711



National Math Olympiads (Uruguay)

Medalist in 2 editions



Maccabi Youth Movement (Uruguay)

Leaded over 500 members and managed an annual budget of 200K USD at the age of 18 and 19. Appointed by popular vote.



Maccabi Theater Group (Uruguay)

Founded a non-profit theater group and produced the first play. Group still active after 10 years: https://goo.gl/wQFyw1